CEVI HERDIAN

Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Enthusiast

Curriculum Vitae

Personal information

Name: Cevi Herdian

Address: Coppistr. 16, 10365, Berlin

Phone: +4917632811289 Mail: itsmecevi@gmail.com

An Enthusiast in Data Analyst & Business Intelligence. Practiced Data Analyst with more than 3 years of experience in extraction, transformation, loaded, statistical interpreting and visualizing various types of dataset. Focusing on KPI Dashboard (Key Performance Indicator) and Predictive Analytics.

- My personal web: https://itsmecevi.github.io/
- My work and ideas in order: https://itsmecevi.github.io/cevipedia/
- My web about Data Visualization & Analytics:
 - o https://itsmecevi.github.io/dataviz-kpi/#
 - https://public.tableau.com/profile/cevi.herdian#!/
- My site about R Shiny, interactive web apps straight from R: https://itsmecevi.github.io/r-shiny-app/

Experience

October 2016 - Present

Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Developer HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences, working student

- Data extraction (ETL process) from different sources such as Excel, Access, SaaS (Software as a Service), Web Service, and from a Database (SQL)
- Developing live stream on-premise and web-based KPI
 Dashboard (Key Performance Indicators) for Federal Statistical
 Office of Germany and for internally used at Human Resources,
 Finance, IT, and Research Department of HTW Berlin
- Ad-Hoc Reporting (Web-based & On-premise)

April 2016 - August 2016

Data Analyst

TradeMachines GmbH, working student

- Collecting machinery data from all website over the world with Web Scraping machine
- Creating all about Data Mining workflow such as preparing, cleaning, formatting, modeling, anomaly detection, classification (without clustering), normalize, and training the dataset of all machinery items for big data environment

April 2015 - December 2015

Business Data Analyst Omnea GmbH, internship & working student

- Financial and Managerial Accounting
- Developing Financial, Managerial, Marketing, and Sales KPI Dashboard (Key Performance Indicator) for internal users and investor

Education

April 2016 - Present

HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences Master of Science - Financial Services & Risk Management

Business Data Analyst Track (Time Series & Predictive Analytics)



CEVI HERDIAN

Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Enthusiast

April 2012 - May 2016

HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences Bachelor of Science - Business Mathematics

Business Data Analyst Track (Mathematical Software)

April 2011 - December 2011

Studientkolleg, HTW Berlin-University of Applied Science Higher education entrance qualification (A-levels)

Natural Sciences

August 2010 - March 2011

Goethe Institute Indonesia & Hartnackschule Berlin

German courses

Award

June 2009 June 2009 October 2009

June 2010 - December 2015: Full Scholarships - Subang Germany Scholarships - Indonesia Top 10 - International Physics Olimpiad - West Java Division 1st Place - International Physics Olimpiad - Subang Division Top 10 - Chemistry Olimpiad - West Java, 2009

Certification & training

August 2015-Present

Data Analyst & Business Intelligence:

- Microsoft Professional Program Data Science
- Microsoft Office Specialist (MOS) Excel
- Microsoft Power BI
- Data Analyst & BI MOOC in Lynda.com, Edx.com, Coursera.com
- ScrumStudy.com: Scrum Fundamental Certified
- Datacamp.com: R programming

All certifications link: https://itsmecevi.gitbook.jo/cert/

Key Skill

I adapt to new concepts and software quickly. Practicing in several methods and software, such as:

- Microsoft Excel
- Power Query & Mashup (M Language)
- Data Model, DAX, Power Pivot
- Power View & Power Maps
- Macro-VBA
- Microsoft Access & SQL
- Microsoft Power BI (on premise & web-based)
- R programming & Shiny app (R web-based)
- Data Analyst:
 - Descriptive & Inferential Statistics
 - Time series & Predictive Analytics
- Key Performance Indicator (KPI)
- Basic Version Control System with Github
- Project Management Know How

Pro Bono

2012 - 2013 2011

Mathematics Tutor, IWKZ e.V.

Member of Education Department PPI Berlin e.V.

Language

Indonesian German & English

Native Intermediate